Hazel Warren papers, 1868-1978 (bulk 1899-1972)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Hazel Warren papers, 1868-1978 (bulk 1899-1972)
MS 410
Hazel Warren
Papers, 1868-1978 (bulk 1899-1972). This collection includes materials relating to the life of writer and Indian Post trader Hazel Warren. Includes daily journals and vacation journals; scrapbooks containing news clippings, photographs, and published magazine articles; news clippings concerning life in Tecumseh, Nebraska, as well as descriptions of Indian tribes of the southwest; family photographs and photographs of reservation scenes; photographic negatives; personal and professional correspondence; published and unpublished manuscripts; and miscellaneous items including decals, buttons, and inscribed Bibles.
13.5 linear feet (about 13,500 items)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Hazel (Woolsey) Warren was born and raised in Tecumseh, Nebraska. After graduating from high school, Ms. Warren worked at a bank in Tecumseh. Later, she worked for a local newspaper, The Tecumseh Chieftain, qualifying as a linotype operator. She first visited Arizona in 1912 when she traveled from Nebraska to Tuba City to vacation with relatives. In 1925 she married Keith Warren in Flagstaff, Arizona, after having known and corresponded with him for several years. After their marriage, the couple managed the Kayenta Trading Post in Kayenta, Arizona, until 1935. They then managed the Cedar Ridge Trading Post in Cameron, Arizona, until their retirement in 1949. Upon retirement, the couple traveled extensively for a time in the western United States and western Canada before settling in Phoenix, Arizona.
Hazel Warren was an avid writer. She began journaling in childhood and continued to keep journals for most of her life. Ms. Warren began submitting feature articles to magazines and newspapers for publication in the late 1920s. Several of these articles were published, primarily in nationally-distributed children's and young adult magazines owned by various religious organizations. She authored some articles under the name "H.W. Warren" as well as others under the pseudonyms "Louise R. Marshall" and "Beatrice Warren." In addition to magazine articles, Ms. Warren wrote a column during the 1940s that was published by The Punxsatawney News in Punxsatawney, Pennsylvania. Ms. Warren also was a hobbyist who enjoyed collecting decals and buttons, among other things, and her column titled "Indian Lore" was published in nationally-distributed hobby magazines during the 1940s.
Organization
This collection is organized into nine series.
Series 1: Journals, 1905-1978
Series 2: Scrapbooks, 1896-1945
Series 3: News clippings, 1894-1975
Series 4: Photographs, 1894-1975
Series 5: Negatives, 1911 (bulk undated)
Series 6: Correspondence, 1899-1978
Series 7: Writings, 1929-1947 (bulk undated)
Series 8: Miscellaneous 1890-1972
Series 9: Oversized, 1929-1948
Scope and Content Note
Papers of writer and Indian trader Hazel Warren. Papers include professional correspondence with publishers; scrapbooks containing news clippings, photographs, published articles and other items; daily journals and vacation journals; a decal collection with decals obtained from places visited as well as decals distributed in support of the war effort during World War II; personal items that belonged to her husband Keith Warren; published magazine articles authored by Ms. Warren; and published and unpublished manuscripts of feature articles and short stories (she authored some articles under the name "H.W. Warren" as well as others under the pseudonyms "Louise R. Marshall" and "Beatrice Warren"). While many of these manuscripts are typewritten, the bulk of them are handwritten (Note: Ms. Warren often recycled paper and would type new articles on the backs of older handwritten articles).
Selected Bibliography:
The Ambassador for Intermediates (Nashville, TN):
Louise R. Marshall:
"Hang Up Your Stocking." December 16, 1934, p. 7.
"Lowell Observatory." June 14, 1936, p. 5
"Weaving on Hopi Mesas." January 6, 1935.
Beatrice Warren:
"Forest Game Sanctuary." Vol. 8, No. 1, January 15, 1939, p. 7.
"Home Off the Range." Vol. 9, No. 2, February 18, 1940, pp. 3, 7-8.
"Indian Legend of Bryce Canyon." Vol. 7, No. 3, March 13, 1938, p. 8.
"Indians Fear Lightening." Vol. 7, No. 6, June 12, 1938, p. 8.
"Indians Share in Fourth." Vol. 8, No. 7, July 2, 1939, p. 8.
"Jasper Park." Vol. 7, No. 7, July 31, 1938, p. 3.
"Shopping with Wool." Vol. 7, No. 1, January 15, 1939, p. 7.
"Wild Life on the Increase." Vol. 7, No. 9, September 4, 1938, p. 7.
"Wilderness Friends in Canada." Vol. 7, No. 10, October 9, 1938, p. 3.
H.W. Warren:
"Bison Herd Roams Range." Vol. 6, No. 8, August 29, 1937, p.6.
"Camels in Arizona." Vol. 6, No. 12, December 19, 1937, p. 6.
"Eating Your Way into Mexico." Vol. 7, No. 1, January 9, 1938, p. 7.
"Floating Gardens." Vol. 6, No. 12, December 26, 1937, p. 7.
"Markets in Mexico." Vol. 7, No. 1, January 23, 1938, p. 3.
"Mirage." Vol. 6, No. 12, December 12, 1937, p. 6.
"We Go Sponging." Vol. 6, No. 6, June 27, 1937, p. 3.
American Cookery:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Thoughts to Beautify Our Homes." pp. 146-149.
Beatrice Warren:
"Have You Had Your Eye Opener?" Vol. XLII, No. 8, March 1938, pp. 475-477.
"Is Yours a Hobby Family?" Vol. XLIV, No. 1, June-July 1939, pp. 31-34.
H.W. Warren:
"Shipboard Human Interest Pictures." p. 92.
The Antiquer (formerly West Coast Hobby Manual):
Hazel Warren:
"Indian Lore: Arrowheads Are Where You Find Them." June 1947, pp. 43-46.
Boy Life:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Death Valley." Vol. LXXII, No. 9, November 26, 1933, pp. 3, 5.
Beatrice Warren:
"The Navajo and His Horse." February 19, 1939, p. 2.
Boy's Comrade:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Candles of the Lord." February 10, 1935.
"Hopi Goes to His Rest." Vol. XXXII, No. 24, June 17, 1934, pp. 190-191.
The Children's Friend (LDS Church, Salt Lake, UT):
Beatrice Warren:
"Noschiti, the Badger." February 1945.
The Cradle Roll Home (Nashville, TN):
Louise R. Marshall:
"Courtesy to Children." Vol. 10, No. 3, July, August, September 1934, p. 2.
"Respect Child's Toys." October, November, December 1935, p. 3.
The Epworth Highroad:
Louise R. Marshall:
"My War Bonnet to You." November 1933, pp. 18, 60.
The Friend:
Louise R. Marshall:
"A Gigantic Irrigation Ditch." November 6, 1932, p. 355.
Beatrice Warren:
"Glory to God on the Heights." November 27, 1938, p. 379.
"In the Royal Family." Vol. 84, No. 52, December 26, 1937, p. 416.
"Wee Kirk O' the Heather." Vol. 85, No. 10, March 6, 1938, p. 80.
"Wonderlands of Utah." Vol. 85, No. 39, September 25, 1938, p. 309.
"Yucca in Role of Soap, Food and Clothing." January 20, 1935, p. 16.
Girl's World (Philadelphia, PA):
H.W. Warren: "Laundry Day in Mexico." Vol. XXX, No. 7, January 22, 1938, p. 120.
The Haversack (Nashville, TN):
Louise R. Marshall:
"Celebrating with a Pow Wow." Vol. XIV, No. 26, June 30, 1935, p. 5.
"Indian Field Day Sports." February 8, 1931, p. 3.
The High Road:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Stonemasons of an Early Day: Pueblo Bonito-The Only Remains of the Culture and Achievements of a Vanished People." January 11, 1931, pp. 6-7.
Home Education (National Kindergarten Association):
Galley Proofs:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Golden Rule Tactics with Our Children." For publication not earlier than March 9, 1935.
"Helping Mother Entertain" For publication not earlier than July 6, 1935.
"Hospitable to Young Visitors." For publication not earlier than October 28, 1933.
The Home Friend Magazine:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Hints for Flower Lovers." June 1934.
Junior Boy (Nashville, TN):
L.R. Marshall:
"A New Way to Pop Corn." October 27, 1929.
Junior Life:
Beatrice Warren:
"Bears in Our Parks." February 25, 1940, pp. 3, 7.
Just Buttons:
Hazel Warren:
"A Little Brown Baby Goes Home." Vol. I, No. 12, September 1943, pp. 2-3, 7.
"We Go Skidding for Buttons." Vol. II, No. 5, February 1944, pp. 4-6, 14.
Lutheran Boys and Girls (Philadelphia, PA):
Louise R. Marshall:
"Arrowheads." March 9, 1935, p. 79.
"Basket Makers." Vol. XXIII, No. 50, December 16, 1933, p. 400.
"Better Than a Tom Tom." February 10, 1934, p. 46.
"Indian Exhibits." October 27, 1934.
"Links of Love." Vol. XXII, No. 12, March 19, 1932, p. 93.
"Picture Rocks." January 14, 1933.
H.W. Warren:
"So Old It's New to Us." Vol. XXVII, No. 36, September 4, 1937, pp. 1-2.
Lutheran Young Folks (Philadelphia, PA):
Louise R. Marshall:
"Back of Beyond." Vol. XXXI, No. 43, September 22, 1934, pp. 338-339.
"Housewife Goes to Market." Vol. XXXIV, No. 29, June 19, 1937, pp. 229-230.
"Little Mud Home in the West." Vol. XXX, No. 41, September 9, 1933, pp. 322-323.
"The Potter and the Clay." March 4, 1933, pp. 110-111.
"Primitive Woman Creates Beauty." October 15, 1932, p. 365.
"Unique Savings Account of a Primitive Race." Vol. XXVIII, No. 48, October 31, 1931, pp. 378-379.
Beatrice Warren:
"Fisherman's Patron Saint." Vol. XXXV, No. 21, April 23, 1938, p. 162.
"Navajo Children Tend the Flocks." Vol. XXXVII, No. 9, January 27, 1940, p. 69.
"Pottery in Mexico." Vol. XXXIV, No. 46, October 16, 1937, p. 363.
"Rodeo and Rituals Mark Fourth." Vol. XXXVI, No. 31, July 1, 1939, p. 245.
"Thank Indians for Vegetable Plate." Vol. XXXV, No. 51, November 19, 1938, p. 402.
"Training to Help Own Tribes." Vol. XXXV, No. 15, March 12, 1938, p. 114.
"West's Most Spectacular Peaks." Vol. XXXVI, No. 32, July 8, 1939, p. 251.
H.W. Warren:
"Land of Flowers." Vol. XXXVI, No. 45, October 7, 1939, p. 355.
New York Herald Tribune: This Week Magazine:
Beatrice Warren:
"Lemon Aid." September 11, 1938, p. 20.
Our Boys and Girls:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Horses in the World's Work." June 25, 1932.
Our Dumb Animals:
Beatrice Warren:
"Animals on Indian Reservation." November 1937, p. 165.
The Rexall Magazine:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Stick to Adhesive." May 1939, pp. 12-15.
The Sentinel for Juniors (Nashville, TN):
Louise R. Marshall:
"Legend of the Petrified Forest." June 2, 1935.
"Wild Life in Yellowstone." Vol. 3, No. 11, November 18, 1934, p. 1.
L.R. Marshall:
"Tractors and Trailers." November 1933.
Beatrice Warren:
"Tribe in an Enchanted Canyon." Vol. 7, No. 1, January 10, 1938, p. 4.
H.W. Warren:
"Love of the Beautiful." Vol. 8, No. 4, April 9, 1939, p. 4.
Southern Agriculturist:
Beatrice Warren:
"Bring in the Wool." June 1939, pp. 8, 15.
The Teacher:
Beatrice Warren:
"Taking Your Pen in Hand." January 1941, pp. 12-13.
'Teens:
Beatrice Warren:
"Enchantment Woven Into Rugs." Vol. 1, No. 3, June 18, 1939, p. 96.
The Trained Nurse and Hospital Review:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Health Studies Among the Indians." July 1936, pp. 41-45.
The Watchword (Dayton, OH):
Louise R. Marshall:
"Indian Children Off to School." Vol. 40, No. 40, October 1, 1933, pp. 8-9.
"Let's Swing Around the 'Magic Circle.'" Vol. 39, No. 26, June 26, 1932, pp. 4-5.
Wee Wisdom:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Christmas Bells Are Ringing." December 1934, pp. 16-17.
West Coast Hobby Manual:
Hazel Warren:
"Indian Lore: Arrowheads." February 1947, pp. 27-29.
"Indian Lore: Borrowed Christmas." December 1946-January 1947, pp. 28-29.
"Indian Lore: A Navajo Silver Button Takes Form." September 1946, pp. 25-26.
"Indian Lore: Running Down His Dinner." March 1947, p. 28.
"Indian Lore: Strange Mingling of Customs." April 1947, p. 31.
"Indian Lore: Will Not Eat Turkey." November 1946, pp. 30, 61.
Working Boy:
H.W. Warren:
"Parrot Guided Hopi to Mesa." Vol. LIV, No. 111, July-September 1937, p. 7.
"Patriotic Farmers." October-December 1945, pp. 6-7.
"Strong Man of Mexico." January-March 1946, p. 12.
"Taxi." Pp. 11-12.
World Friends:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Celebrating With Our Indian Friends." July 1932, pp. 8-10, 23.
"A Lively Job." Vol. 5, No. 11, August 1932, p. 1.
Young Catholic Messenger:
Louise R. Marshall:
"A Prehistoric Autograph Album." May 1, 1936, p. 262.
Young People:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Mud Dance." July 18, 1936, p. 231.
"The Original American Cook." August 1, 1931.
"Where Neighbors Are Neighbors." Vol. LII, No. 7, February 13, 1932, pp. 50-51.
Young People's Paper:
Beatrice Warren:
"Give Me a Home on the Plains." October 1, 1939, pp. 1-2.
"With a Pattern in Her Mind." October 15, 1939, pp. 20-23.
The Youth's Comrade:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Origin of Easter Egg." p. 8.
Youth's World:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Bath Day in Navajo-Land." April 11, 1931.
[No periodical title listed]:
Louise R. Marshall:
"Eating Habits of the Modern Navajos." pp. 26-27.
"Fire Dance of the Navajos: A Primitive Method of Combating Disease." pp. 22-23.
"Kaibab Squirrel." October 1, 1932.
"Luggage for a Voyage."
"Sacramental Feast of the Navajos."
Access Terms
Warren, Hazel (Woolsey)
Warren, Henry Keith
Indian Traders-Arizona
Trading Posts-Arizona
Cedar Ridge Trading Post
Kayenta Trading Post
Navajo Indians
Hopi Indians
Container List
- Series 1: Journals 1905-1978, 5 linear feet (about 5,000 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
  This series contains journals kept by Hazel Warren. Most of the journals are handwritten and they span from her childhood until a few years before her death. The bulk of the journals are general in topic matter, usually documenting daily activities for Ms. Warren. Two vacation journals are included that document a Mexico trip in 1935 and a Canadian trip in 1949-1950.
  - Canada. 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General. (Box 1, Folder 2-16)
  - General. 1905-1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - General. 1906-1907 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - General. 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - General. 1909-1911 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - General. 1911-1913 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - General. 1919-1914 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - General. 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - General. 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - General. 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - General. 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - General. 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - General. 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - General. 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - General. 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - General. 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - General. 1924 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - General. 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - General. 1926 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General. 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General. 1928 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - General. 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General. 1930 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General. 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - General. 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - General. 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - General. 1934-1936 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General. 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - General. 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - General. 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - General. 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - General. 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - General. 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - General. 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - General. 1940-1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - General. 1942 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General. 1942-1946 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - General. 1943 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - General. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - General. 1945 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - General. 1945-1961 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - General. 1946 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General. 1946-1949 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General. 1947 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - General. 1948 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - General. 1949 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - General. 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - General. 1950 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - General. 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - General. 1951 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - General. 1952 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - General. 1953 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - General. 1954 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - General. 1954-1959 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General. 1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General. 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - General. 1956 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - General. 1957 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - General. 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7-10)
  - General. 1959 (Box 4, Folder 11-13)
  - General. 1960 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - General. 1961 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
  - General. 1962 (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
  - General. 1963 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - General. 1964 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - General. 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - General. 1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - General. 1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - General. 1968 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - General. 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - General. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - General. 1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - General. 1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - General. 1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - General. 1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - General. 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - General. 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - General. 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - General. 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Mexico. 1935 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Series 2: Scrapbooks, 1896-1945, 1.5 linear feet (about 1,500 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
  The bulk of the series contains scrapbooks with news clippings of general trivial matters and events of interest to Ms. Warren (much of the trivial information found in the scrap-booked clippings is similar to that found in the popular "Ripley's Believe it Or Not" syndicated column). Additionally, there is a scrapbook devoted to animals and insects and one dedicated to birds. Three scrapbooks contain material on Indian tribes of the southwest. Two scrapbooks contain articles published by Ms. Warren. Two scrapbooks are dedicated to matters that occurred in Ms. Warren's hometown of Tecumseh, Nebraska. Finally, there is a scrapbook that contains decals collected by Ms. Warren. (Note: three oversized scrapbooks are located in Series 9: Oversized).
  - Animals and Insects. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Birds. (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - General. (Box 6, Folder 3-14)
  - General. 1869-1971 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - General. 1928-1945 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - General. 1929-1931 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - General. 1935-1945 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - General. 1936 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Indian Magazine Articles." 1933-1941 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Indian Stories." 1931-1937 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Navajos, Zunis, Taos, and Other Tribes." (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Published Articles-Louise Marshall (Hazel Warren). 1931-1938 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Stories. 1929-1931 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Tecumseh, Nebraska. 1895-1945 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Tecumseh, Nebraska. 1897-1943 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Series 3: News Clippings, 1894-1975, 1.0 linear foot (about 1,000 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
  This series contains news clippings of general interest to Hazel Warren as well as news articles concerning her or her family. Additionally, there are issues of The Punxsutawney News containing a regular column written by Ms. Warren.
  - Birdwatching. 1962-1971 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - The Coconino Sun (Flagstaff, Arizona). (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - The Coconino Sun (Flagstaff, Arizona). 1929-1932 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - General. (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
  - General. 1922-1959 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - General. 1960-1975 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Goulding, Harry. 1953-1975 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Grant, Zora. 1934-1975 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Green Art. 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Grey, Zane. (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Grey, Zane. 1954-1972 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Johnson County Journal (Tecumseh, Nebraska). 1894 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Marble, H.P. (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Marble, H.P. 1911-1927 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - The Navajo Language Monthly (Adahooniligii). 1943-1949 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - The Navajo Times. 1969-1974 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Southwest Tourist News. (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Warren, Hazel ( The Chieftain-Tecumseh, Nebraska). 1931-1958 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Warren, Hazel (Miscellaneous). (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Warren, Hazel (Miscellaneous). 1937 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Warren, Hazel ( Punxsutawney News-Punxsutawney, PA). 1941-1945 (Box 8, Folder 4-12)
  - Warren, Keith. 1917-1972 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Wetherills. 1929-1975 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Woolsey Family. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Woolsey Family. 1912-1971 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Series 4: Photographs,. 1894-1975, 1.0 linear foot (about 1,000 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
  This series contains photograph albums as well as folders containing loose photographs. Included are photographs of family members, photographs taken on various trips, and photographs of reservation scenes.
  - Albums (California and Hawaii). 1912-1915 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Albums (General). (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Albums (Mexico). (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
  - Albums (Nebraska). (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - British Columbia, Canada. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - California. 1937-1939 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Cedar Ridge Trading Post Employees. (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Colorado. (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Crater Lake, Oregon. 1937 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Death Valley. (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Grand Canyon, Bryce Canyon, and Zion National Parks. (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Grand Canyon National Park. 1939 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Lac La Hache, B.C., Canada. 1961 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Marble Family. (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Marble Family. 1892-1955 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Mexico. 1936 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 8, Folder 34-35)
  - Miscellaneous. 1936-1972 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Reservation Scenes. (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Reservation Scenes. 1911-1940 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Warren, Hazel. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Warren, Hazel. 1893-1963 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Warren, Keith. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Warren, Keith. 1908-1949 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Woolsey Family. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Woolsey Family. 1868-1969 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Wetherill, John. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Yellowstone. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Yellowstone. 1936-1937 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Series 5: Negatives, 1911 (bulk undated), .5 linear foot (about 500 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
  This series consists of folders containing loose negatives. Included are negatives of images of Hazel Warren, a trip to Mexico, and reservation scenes.
  - Mexico. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 9, Folder 11-13)
  - Reservation Scenes. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Snake Dance. 1911 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Warren, Hazel. (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Series 6: Correspondence, 1899-1978, 1.0 linear foot (about 1,000 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
  This series contains correspondence including childhood correspondence between Ms. Warren and her niece, Zora Marble; childhood correspondence between Ms. Warren and her schoolteacher; correspondence between Ms. Warren and Keith Warren while he was stationed in France during World War I; and professional correspondence with magazine editors. Ms. Warren's professional correspondence also includes a letter from "Family Circus" cartoonist Bill Keane. Additionally, the series contains greeting cards and postcards sent to the Warrens.
  - Greeting Cards. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Greeting Cards. 1909-1975 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Postcards. (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Postcards. 1906-1919 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Postcards. 1931-1939 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Postcards. 1940-1949 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Postcards. 1950-1955 (Box 9, Folder 23-24)
  - Postcards. 1956-1959 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Postcards. 1960-1969 (Box 9, Folder 26-27)
  - Postcards. 1970-1978 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Professional. 1928-1971 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Warren, Hazel. (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Warren, Hazel. 1899-1929 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Warren, Hazel. 1932-1939 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Warren, Hazel. 1940-1949 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Warren, Hazel. 1950-1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Warren, Hazel. 1960-1969 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Warren, Hazel. 1970-1978 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Warren, Keith. 1918-1960 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Series 7: Writings, 1929-1947 (bulk undated), 1.0 linear foot (about 1,000 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.